原作者名：Scott Manley
视频来源：youtu.be/cmQfWuFbLNg
原视频发布日期：20201024
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是Scott Manley
And if you've been paying attention to space news this week
如果你一直在关注本周的太空新闻的话
then you've been hearing a lot about OSIRIS-REx.
那么你已经听到了很多关于冥王号的消息
关于冥王号采样的中文科普文章可见 @haibaraemily的回答
www.zhihu.com/question/426424697/answer/1533163716
And it's close encounter with the asteroid Bennu.
还有它与小行星贝努的接触的新闻
Some places have called it touching the surface.
有些地方称它为触及表面
Others called it a landing.
也有人说是着陆
Some people said it was booping the surface
有些人说它是在表面上戳了下
and some said it was punching an asteroid.
也有人说是在给小行星打孔
But being the professional that I am
但如我一般专业的人士
I prefer to describe it as blowing a raspberry on the belly of a four and a half billion year old asteroid.
会把它描述为在45亿年前的小行星的肚子上吹走一串树莓
And that was really the culmination of OSIRIS-REx's mission at the asteroid Bennu.
这就是冥王号在小行星贝努的任务的高潮部分
So OSIRIS-REx, its main purpose was to go to an ancient Carbonaceous chondrite asteroid.
那么冥王号的主要目的是去一个古老的碳质球粒陨石小行星(C-型小行星)
Carbonaceous chondrites are asteroids which are very very old.
C-型小行星是一种非常古老的小行星
They have unprocessed material from the very earliest part of the Solar System.
它们有来自太阳系最早期的原始物质
If you find a rock on the surface of the earth
如果你在地球表面发现了一块石头
that rock might have material in it from when the earth formed
那么这块石头中可能有地球形成时的物质
but since then it's been melted, spat out of a volcano, weathered, metamorphosized,
但从那时起 它就被融化了 从火山里吐出来 风化了 变形了
perhaps gone back into the crust and then back into the mantle and maybe come up again, right.
也许会回到地壳中 然后回到地幔中 也许会再次出现 对吧
It is not pristine material.
那么这就不是原始的材料了
But Carbonaceous chondrites they're very dark.
但碳质球粒陨石的颜色很深
They're full of carbon minerals from low oxygen environments.
它们充满了来自低氧环境的碳矿物
And it looks like it's believed that
而这看起来让人们相信
these objects are relatively unprocessed since the earliest part of the Solar System.
在太阳系最初形成之后 这些天体基本就没变过
So they're very important to understanding how the Solar System formed.
那么它们对了解太阳系的形成就非常重要
So OSIRIS-REx launched to one of these was named Bennu
那么冥王号就被发射到其中一个这样的天体叫贝努
and it arrived in December of 2018.
并在2018年12月抵达
And spent about a year looking at the surface trying to find a target that it could sample.
之后花了大约一年的时间来观察这颗小行星的表面 试图找到一个可以取样的目标
And they had a slight problem because when they originally looked at Bennu as a candidate
而他们遇到了一个小问题 因为最初把贝努选入的时候
they thought based upon the thermal inertia that
根据热惯性 他们认为
this was probably had a lot of particulate material
这颗小行星可能有很多颗粒物质
and it would be like going to a sandy beach where they could just grab a you know chunk off the surface.
这就像去一个沙滩上 他们可以从其表面上抓一大块儿(样本)
It was completely wrong.
但这是完全错误的
It was full of giant boulders sticking out all over the place.
这里到处都是巨大的石块
And they had to work very hard to find areas on the surface they could sample.
所以他们必须非常努力地在表面寻找可以取样的区域
Not only that but because of these big boulders
不仅如此 由于这些大石头的存在
they actually had to change the way they plan to navigate the spacecraft during the sampling.
事实上 他们不得不改变计划在取样过程中对航天器进行导航的方式
翻译成激光测距仪的原因 www.zhihu.com/question/425527100/answer/1525638472
Originally they were just going to use Lidar to tell them when they were close to the surface
原本他们只是打算用激光测距仪来决定什么时候接近地面
and with that they figured they could get within 25 meters of their sample site and that would be fine.
而有了这个 他们就觉得可以在25米以内的取样点进行测量了
When they looked at the sample sites they realized they would need precision of about five meters
在查看样本点时 他们意识到精度需要5米左右
or they ran the risk of hitting you know boulders nearby.
否则就可能撞到附近的巨石上
And one of the boulders next to one of the sites was christened mount doom
而其中一个地点旁边的巨石被命名为厄运山
because it would have spelled certain doom for the spacecraft you had it actually hit it.
因为如果航天器撞上了它 就会发生灭顶之灾
So they actually performed a software upgrade on the spacecraft
所以他们对航天器进行了软件升级
to give it optical navigation capabilities where it could look at images from the camera
给它增加了光学导航功能 使它可以查看来自相机的图像
identify important features and track those to make sure it was on course.
并识别跟踪重要的特征 以确保航向不偏离
So during the sampling procedure when we were watching it live on NASA TV
那么在取样过程中 当我们在NASA电视上观看它的现场直播时
we could only see a simulation of what was going on.
我们只能看到实时的模拟过程
They had been rehearsing this several times.
而他们已经演练了好几次了
They had the data. They had the images.
他们有数据和图像
But the live data coming back from the spacecraft was only 40 bits per second.
但从航天器传回的实时数据 只有40bit/s的速度
So it was tiny breadcrumbs telling us how fast it was going, how accurate it thought it was.
这样面包屑般的带宽只能告诉我们航天器的速度 精度之类的信息
The reason for this very low bit rate is
之所以带宽如此之小
when it's focused on sampling the surface of the asteroid
是因为当它专注在小行星表面取样的时候
it's in an orientation to reduce the damage to itself.
它会采用减少伤害的特定朝向
It doesn't care about pointing the high gain antenna at the earth.
这种朝向并不会把高增益天线指向地球
It cares about making sure that it can sample the asteroid.
而是为了确保它能对小行星进行取样
So we got the messages that perform the sampling
那么我们得到了执行取样的信息
and it headed off into space at a blistering rate of 40 centimeters per second
之后它就以0.4m/s的高速 飞向太空
根据NASA官网数据，小行星贝努的逃逸速度在0.15m/s和2m/s之间
solarsystem.nasa.gov/asteroids-comets-and-meteors/asteroids/101955-bennu/by-the-numbers/
which may sound slow but is in fact greater than the escape velocity of the asteroid in question.
这听起来很慢 但实际上比贝努的逃逸速度还要大
After that it was able to of course reorient
在那之后 它当然能够调整方向
and beam the images back to the surface of the earth.
并将图像传送回地球表面
And we then saw the next day this glorious sequence
第二天我们就看到了这一串壮丽的画面
showing the spacecraft descending, touching the surface and then well as I said blowing a raspberry
显示了航天器的下降 对地面的接触 然后就像我说的 吹走了一串树莓
and this was probably one heck of a raspberry.
而这可能会是非常有名的一串树莓
It could have blown maybe a ton of material out of this asteroid in the end.
它可能从这颗小行星上吹了一吨的物质出来
Now the way the sample container works is it's a disk like sample object.
那么样本容器的工作原理是这样的 它是一个圆盘状的取样器
And it blows nitrogen around the outside in a ring
然后它会用氮气向外面的环状空间里吹气
and that's supposed to go down and some of it expands outwards but some of it expands inwards.
而氮气会向下压过去 一些会向内扩张 一些会向外扩张
and forces material up into the center of the collection system.
并推动材料进入收集系统的中心
And from there it's blown outwards through vents in the side
之后再通过那里 也就是侧面的通风口向外吹出
and on the way to that, it hits grills but it also passes through a flap.
这样的通风口上有栅格板和盖子
It's a disc actually, a mylar plastic disc
实际上 这个取样器是一个聚脂塑料圆盘
that gets pushed out as the the atmosphere is blowing.
在吹气的时候 盖子就会被推出来
And then once that's stopped it's supposed to flip back and seal all the material they've got in there.
然后一旦停止吹气 就翻转回来 并密封所有已经收集进来的材料
And they were wanting to get 60 grams of material
而他们想要得到60克的材料
that was their sort of minimum for success.
这差不多是他们认为的达成任务成功的目标
Now I didn't make a video after this these images
那么 我并没有立刻在他们发布这些照片后制作视频
because I was waiting to find out just how much they thought they had.
因为我在等待他们弄清样本的质量
One of the plans was they were going to take the camera
其中一个计划是使用相机
and hold the sampling device up to the camera
让取样装置对准相机
and take some images and see does it look like it has anything in it.
并拍摄一些图像 看看它里面装了多少
And boy does it have something in it. It has possibly way more than they expected
但是兄啊 这里面确实有货 而且比预计的还多很多
It looks like when they touched the surface
看起来就像他们接触到表面的时候
they went and pushed the sampling head inside the asteroid
整个取样头都推入到小行星内部了
and they got a lot more than they bargained for.
于是他们得到了远多于预期的部分
When they started taking these images off the sampling head
在他们拍下这些取样头的照片时
they noticed that there was a lot of particles floating around it.
他们注意到 有很多颗粒漂浮在它周围
And as they examined it more they noticed that the mylar one waste disc was open
而当他们进一步检查时 发现聚脂盘是打开的
so it was actually being propped open by some large object a few centimeters across.
那么这个聚酯盘实际上是被一些直径几厘米的大物体撑开的
These were jammed in there by the force by the gas.
这些东西在气体的推动下卡在了那里
And because this was open that meant that material was able to leak out.
而因为它是开放的 这意味着材料会泄漏出来
And every time they were moving this sample head around to get a new orientation
而且每当他们移动取样头改变姿态的时候
they would be imparting kinetic energy to the particles
这样的动作都会把动能传给微粒
and those were bouncing around and some of those were escaping.
这样微粒就会弹来弹去 甚至逃逸
So while they might have a kilogram or more of material,
所以虽然可能采到了1kg甚至更多的材料
they're slowly losing it every time they move this.
但每动一次就会慢慢丢失材料
The original plan was to weigh this canister
原本计划是要称这个罐子
and the way they would do this
而称量的方法
was to put the canister out on the end of the longest arm position and then rotate the spacecraft
是把样本罐放在取样臂的最远端 然后旋转航天器
and from that they would be able to determine the moment of inertia of the system.
由此他们就能确定系统的惯性矩
And therefore how much it had changed from having mass in there.
这样就能确定质量的变化量
Now because they see that they likely have a fair amount of material
那么因为他们看到材料的量很可能已经很多了
and that they're losing it whenever they're moving it
而每当材料移动的时候 就会有一定的损失
they've decided that they're going to cut that out.
于是他们已经决定 要砍掉测量质量的这个操作
And they are re-prioritizing the entire set of operations
而他们正重新安排整个行动的优先次序
to try and put it into the sample return canister or as quickly as possible.
尽量且尽快把材料放进样品返回罐里
So on the side of the spacecraft there is a re-entry vehicle, a sample return capsule.
那么在航天器的侧面有一个再入飞行器或者说一个样品返回舱
It will hinge open.
它可以用铰链打开
And in there there's a receptacle where they can latch this canister onto it. Put it in place.
返回舱里有个容器 可以锁住这个罐子 并固定好
They will then have to detach it from the sampling arm.
当然 样品罐得从取样臂上卸下来
And this is not a trivial operation because there's mechanical joints here
而这不是一个简单的操作 因为这里有机械接头
and there's electrical connections. There's new mat.
还有电气连接 新的垫子
There's gas connections that they have to cut.
同时还得切断气体的连接
So all these things will be severed once they're sure that it's latched in place.
那么所有这些在样品罐锁住以后都会被切断
Pull that back and then close the container.
之后会收回取样臂 然后关闭容器
Now there are concerns because there's a lot of material floating around that
现在有些担心 因为有很多材料漂浮在周围
they might try to push it in and find there's a chunk of rock that's getting in the way.
在试着把样品罐推进去的时候可能会被石头卡住
They might try to close the sample return capsule and find that there's debris that's getting in the way there.
可能在关闭样品返回舱的时候被石头卡住
So they are not out of the woods right now.
所以他们现在还没有脱离险境
They need to get this and stow it
他们需要得到并存储样品
and it's going to be a slow operation.
而这将是一个缓慢的操作
The faster they move, the more material they're going to lose.
一旦移动的速度越快  就会失去越多的材料
The slower they move, the more time they have to lose material.
但移动得越慢 就会有越多的时间失去材料
They're trying to figure out how to do this quickly and slowly at the same time
他们正试图找出一种方法 来同时既快又慢地完成这项工作
which is not something that you normally have to do.
而这通常不是你要做的事情
Some other interesting numbers that came out of this by the way was that
顺便说一下 得到的其他一些有趣的数字
when the sampling canister hit the surface of Bennu
当取样罐撞上贝努的表面时
they registered a very small acceleration in it.
他们记录了一个非常小的加速度
What they didn't register was any flexure.
但没有记录到任何的弯曲
There's a spring on the arm that's supposed to absorb shocks.
取样臂上有一个缓冲弹簧
And this spring depresses at a force of 70 newtons right.
而这个弹簧的触发压力是70牛顿
That's about seven kilograms 15 pounds if you're still speaking imperial.
这大约是7kg或者说15lb 如果你在用英制
So this hit the surface and that did not register.
那么航天器撞到了表面却没有记录到压力
So they didn't get more than seven kilograms of force pushing them back.
那么撞到表面的时候并没有遇到这样7kg的力
So they hit the surface and while there's an acceleration it's less than you know.
那么这样的撞击加速度比预计的要小
It basically doesn't change the speed of the spacecraft.
基本上不会改变航天器的速度
So this hit the surface at four centimeters per second
那么撞击表面的时候 航天器的速度是0.04m/s
and kept going into the surface for about six seconds.
之后大概6s都在不断冲入表面
Then they light the thrusters and it starts to come back out
然后他们启动了推进器 航天器才开始往回走
and they reckon that it might have gone as far as half a meter.
而他们估计航天器在这段时间中已经运动了半米之多
You know a couple of feet inside the interior of this asteroid.
这也差不多就是小行星内部几十厘米的距离
So yeah that's great they had a lot of material to sample.
那么 很好 这可以取样到很多材料
The asteroid is made of very loosely connected material that it gets pushed out of the way.
这颗小行星是由非常松散的材料构成 以至于都被航天器推了出去
There'll be a lot written about this and there's a lot of data coming back.
由此会产生很多论文 会传回很多数据
But hopefully there's a lot of material coming back.
但希望能带回很多材料
But it's going to be a while before they get this.
但是距离材料返回地球还需要一段时间
At this point they haven't performed any burns to stop.
到目前为止 他们还没有进行任何停止航天器运动的发动机点火
They've basically canceled any further operations until they get this stowed.
基本上已经取消了任何进一步的操作 直到材料完成了存储
And so by that point they're done with this, they're gonna be long gone from Bennu.
那么到存储好材料的时候 他们距离贝努应该就很远了
So this is their departure from Bennu was then blowing a raspberry on the surface
所以他们离开贝努的时候 是在小行星表面吹走了一串树莓
and at this point they're all saying so long Bennu. Thanks for all the gravel.
而此时他们都在说再见贝努 感谢所有你提供的砂石
We'll see you later.
再见
Well hopefully we won't see you later because Bennu.
当然希望我们不要再见
One of the reasons why Bennu was chosen is because its orbit regularly brings it close to the planet earth
选择贝努的原因之一是它的轨道经常接近地球
which means that getting to it is pretty easy in terms of delta-v
这意味着 从速度增量的角度来看 到达它是非常容易的
and getting back is relatively easy because it regularly comes close to the earth.
并且回来也相对容易 因为它经常接近地球
But that also means it has a chance of hitting earth.
但这也意味着它有机会撞击地球
So hopefully we don't see Bennu up close later at any your future time that I'm going to be around for.
那么希望贝努不会在我们所处的未来中有接近的机会
Either way look it's great to see OSIRIS-REx has got this material.
不管怎样 很高兴看到冥王号得到了这个材料
I'm hoping they get it in the canister
我希望他们能把它装进罐子里
and I can't wait to see it return in 2023.
我迫不及待地想看到它在2023年返回地球
It's going to streak across the sky
它将在天空中飞速划过
and there's a good chance I might actually be able to see it you know in my part of the world.
而且很有可能在我所处的世界中看到它
It's gonna land in Utah.
尽管它将在犹他州降落
But it'll be coming up from the the south west at very high speed and hitting the atmosphere.
但它会从西南方向以极高的速度飞来 撞击大气层
It'll get captured in the air.
它会在空中被捕获
（译者注，可能是口胡，并未查到任何空中回收的说法，也可能单纯指在空气中被地球捕获）
Oh yes it'll be so exciting.
哦 是的 这将是如此令人兴奋
But yeah, OSIRIS-REx, a marvelous mission.
是的 冥王号 一个了不起的任务
Hope that they managed to get this back.
希望他们能把样品拿回来
Hopefully they don't run into any extra problems.
希望他们不会遇到任何额外的问题
But that's it. See you in 2023.
就这样吧 2023年见
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 切记 注意飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]